<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&lt;MickGeekLabs/&gt;</title>
    <link>https://mickgeeklabs.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on &lt;MickGeekLabs/&gt;</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 10:43:22 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mickgeeklabs.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Developer Issue Tracking Scheme -- DITS</title>
      <link>https://mickgeeklabs.org/projects/dits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 10:43:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mickgeeklabs.org/projects/dits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DITS (Developer Issue Tracking System) is a purpose-built issue tracker designed exclusively for individual software developers. It eliminates the &amp;ldquo;collaboration tax&amp;rdquo; of&#xA;team-oriented tools by providing friction-less issue capture, sub-100ms interactions, and deep bidirectional Git integration, offering a keyboard-first,&#xA;flow-state-optimized experience across web, desktop, mobile, and IDE platforms while ensuring complete data portability and user ownership.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating A Website</title>
      <link>https://mickgeeklabs.org/blog/my-first-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 09:09:30 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mickgeeklabs.org/blog/my-first-blog-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well here it is.  I finally built my first website, my own place on the internet.&#xA;I have always wanted to build a blog and post interesting stuff, but could never find a good way to accomplish this.  I have tried building Hugo sites before, but&#xA;it never worked out.  I tried using one of Hugo&amp;rsquo;s themes, but trying to modify one of those to suit my needs turned into a nightmare.  Well, here I am again using&#xA;Hugo to build a website and a blog, this time with the help of AI.  Starting from a blank slate or trying to use one of Hugo&amp;rsquo;s themes just didn&amp;rsquo;t work for me.  If I&#xA;can get something I like to start with, then I have no problem taking off from there.  What I have so far looks good and I like it.  This is a work in progress and I&amp;rsquo;ll&#xA;be making changes as I go along.  I&amp;rsquo;ll see how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
